Finding Aid for the Connie Lembark Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Connie Lembark Papers
2016
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0709
3.75 linear feet
Biography
Connie Wertheimer Lembark was born on March 8, 1934 in Omaha, Nebraska and was raised in Los Angeles, California. She married Daniel Lembark in 1955. Not long after they were married Connie and Danny got involved in the burgeoning art scene of mid-century California. Connie worked in various art galleries in Los Angeles befriending artists represented at these galleries.
In particular she became friends with Sam Francis and later edited The Prints of Sam Francis: A Catalog Raisonne. She and Danny traveled extensively visiting museums and galleries around the world.
In 1992 the Lembarks moved to Nashville, Tennessee. They stayed in Nashville for eight years before moving back to Los Angeles in 2000. While in Nashville Connie and Danny connected with the arts community and assisted in facilitating some important exhibitions of artists that had not previously had a venue in Nashville.
In 2008 Connie and writer Kristin Makholm published Art Adventures of Connie Lembark using photographs Connie and Danny had taken throughout the years of their artist friends and recounting stories of these seminal artists.
Danny passed away in 2003 and on November 27, 2011 Connie passed away in Los Angeles, California. They have one son, Steven Lembark.
Scope and Content
The Connie Lembark Papers consist of 11 boxes (4.5 linear feet) of photographs and notes accumulated through the lives of Daniel and Connie Lembark and date from 1970 to 2008. The majority of the papers are color photographs from the couple’s trips in the United States and abroad. Included in these papers are the drafts and proofs of the 2008 book the Art Adventures of Connie Lembark and a few video tapes and DVDs of artists and events from the 1990s and 2000s.
- Subject Files
  - Herb Alpert (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Archives of American Art Journal, vol. 37, nos. 3-4, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Article clippings (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Christo (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Connie’s Life Story (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence –Art (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sam Francis Catalog –The Prints of Sam Francis (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sam Francis Work (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Graphic Arts Council Newsletter –Article by Connie on Sam Francis (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lembark Sample Artwork (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Roy Lichtenstein (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Kenneth Noland (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - George Rickey (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Robert Ryman (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bener Venet Studio (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Vision of 10: A Documentary Project by Tom Neff (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bill Wegman (Box 1, Folder 18)
- The Art Adventures of Connie Lembark
  - Draft Copy, Part 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Draft Copy, Part 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chapter 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chapter 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chapter 3 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chapter 4 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chapter 5 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chapter 6 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Proof Copy, November 7, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Proof Copy, November 23, 1008 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Dust Jackets (3) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Photographs, 1970, 1973, 1979, 1983-1985, 1989
  - Italy Trip, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Barcelona, Spain Trip –Joan Miro, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Barcelona, Spain Trip –Joan Miro, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Barcelona, Spain Trip –Joan Miro, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Barcelona, Spain Trip –Joan Miro, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Barcelona, Spain Trip –Joan Miro, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Barcelona, Spain Trip –Joan Miro, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Barcelona, Spain Trip –Joan Miro, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Barcelona, Spain Trip –Joan Miro, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Barcelona, Spain Trip –Joan Miro, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Photographs, 1990-1992
  - 1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Kenneth Noland, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Kenneth Noland, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Kenneth Noland, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Kenneth Noland, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Kenneth Noland, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Kenneth Noland, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Kenneth Noland, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Sam Francis Book Signing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Sam Francis Book Signing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Sam Francis Book Signing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Sam Francis Book Signing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Sam Francis Book Signing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sam Francis Book Signing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Sam Francis Book Signing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Sam Francis Book Signing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Sam Francis Book Signing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Sam Francis Book Signing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Sam Francis Book Signing, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Photographs, 1994, 1996
  - Art Installations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Art Installations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Art Installations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Art Installations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Art Installations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Art Installations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Art Installations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Art Installations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Art Installations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Art Installations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Art Installations (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Art Installations, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Nice, France Trip, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Photographs, 1997-2000s
  - 1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1999 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 2000s (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Photographs, 2000
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - 2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Family, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Family, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Family, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Family, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Family, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Photographs, 2000-2001
  - Basketball Hall of Fame, MA Trip, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Basketball Hall of Fame, MA Trip, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Canton, Ohio –Football Hall of Fame Trip, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cooperstown, NY –Baseball Hall of Fame Trip, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cooperstown, NY –Baseball Hall of Fame Trip, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cooperstown, NY –Baseball Hall of Fame Trip, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cooperstown, NY –Baseball Hall of Fame Trip, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Greenbrier, WV Trip, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Greenbrier, WV Trip, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Kansas City Trip, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Kansas City Trip, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Kansas City Trip, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Kansas City Trip, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Kansas City Trip, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - 2001 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Photographs, 2001-2002
  - Arizona Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Arizona Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Arizona Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Las Vegas, NM Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Las Vegas, NM Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Las Vegas, NM Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Las Vegas, NM Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Las Vegas, NM Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Las Vegas, NM Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Las Vegas, NM Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Las Vegas, NM Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Las Vegas, NM Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Las Vegas, NM Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania and New Jersey Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Pennsylvania and New Jersey Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Pennsylvania and New Jersey Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Pennsylvania and New Jersey Trip, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - 2002 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Charleston, SC Trip, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Charleston, SC Trip, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Charleston, SC Trip, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Charleston, SC Trip, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Russia Trip, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Russia Trip, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Russia Trip, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Russia Trip, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Photographs, 2005, 2008, undated
  - 2005 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 2005 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - 2005 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 2005 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 2005 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Daniel Lembark Distribution Center, CA, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Nashville, TN, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Nashville, TN, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Nashville, TN, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Nashville, TN, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - 2008 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - 2008 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - 2008 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - 2008 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - 2008 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Sam Francis Artwork (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Sam Francis Artwork –Transparencies (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Barcelona, Spain, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Barcelona, Spain, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Barcelona, Spain, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Barcelona, Spain, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Middle East Trip, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Middle East Trip, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Middle East Trip, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Middle East Trip, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Middle East Trip, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Middle East Trip, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Middle East Trip, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Videos
  - Sam Francis Lecture (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Sam Francis Short Reel by Jeff Perkins 30min (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Connie Lembark –Book Signing (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Connie Lembark/Andre Emmerich Gallery, September 24, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Connie Lembark/Andre Emmerich GalleryVideo of Frank Stella talk at Albright Knox –DVD (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Connie Lembark/Andre Emmerich GalleryVideo Inventory of Connie and Dan Lembark’s Collection, April 25, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Fletcher Benton Sculpture, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 7)